ANDREW DOAK, M.F.A.

W. LIVETERM.DOAK.STUDIO GH. github.com/andrewdoak Ll. https://www.linkedin.com/in/doak-andrew/ M. 615-957-2341 E. andrew@doak.studio

DEVELOPER SUMMARY

Servant-leader, team player, dot-connecting thinker with a proven history of synthesizing and implementing abstract ideas and managing complex projects. Current goal is to build beautiful, useful, innovative tech products. This work is still fueled by the same "core" it always has been: creativity, superb attention to detail, dedication, open-mindedness, a growth mentality, emotional intelligence, and thoughtful, context-sensitive communication.

SKILLS SUMMARY

FRONT-END HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React, Redux, p5.js, UI/UX design, Figma, Tachyons CSS **BACK-END** MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Node.js

SOFTWARE Photoshop, Lightroom, Capture One, Adobe Premiere, DaVinci Resolve, InDesign, Illustrator COMPREHENSIVE Project management, networking, command-line, version control (Git/GitHub), writing (technical, persuasive, creative, academic), public speaking, teaching, team leadership, idea generation, problem solving, foreign language translation, color management, digital & analog printmaking, camera systems, cinematography, audio recording, studio lighting, custom framing & presentation, design systems, typography

TECHNICAL TRAINING & PROJECTS

PER SCHOLAS | FULL-STACK ENGINEER (MERN Stack) 2023, October

Graduate of a competitive full-stack developer boot-camp with a social mission:

Acquired the equivalent of a year's hands-on training in 15 weeks: over 900+ hours of technical & professional education—including self-study—with a focus on programmatic thinking & debugging

MATCHING GAME | HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, p5.js

GITHUB | WEBSITE

- Created a visually-rich, challenging, fun browser-based typing game that involves hand-eye coordination and speed; learned and implemented an additional JS library designed for creative coding under a tight deadline
- Added game features, such as criteria for losing, different round lengths, and game speed based on user-testing
- Final product commended for risk-taking, dedication, and for learning a new JS framework for the project (p5.js)

VIRTUAL MUSEUM | ReactJS, CSS, Rest API

GITHUB | WEBSITE

- Built a React Single Page Application that searches the Art Institute of Chicago's API, returns data from the search, and allows users to explore the collection, discover new works, or research known works
- Conducted user testing and modified data displayed from the API call based on observing real-time use
- Designed and implemented a tasteful UI—one user's positive response: "feels like a real online museum"

THE VEGETALIST | MongoDB, Express, Mongoose, React, Node.js, RestAPI

GITHUB | WEBSITE

- Envisioned data architecture, user stories, and visual design of a gardening app that adds efficiency and fun to square-foot garden planning—in particular tracking of complex plant relationships and timelines
- Created a full-stack single-page-application built on MERN architecture that incorporates the ability to fully manipulate user and vegetable data; which facilitates planning & maintaining a square foot garden plot
- Potential users—many of whom had never gardened before—became inspired to try gardening for the first time, while others applauded real-world problem solving through software development

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY

Coursework in: Information Technology, Human-Computer-Interaction, Graphic Design, Designing for Physical Technology, Digital Cinema Production

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS OWNER, CONTRACTOR Foxtrot, Caviar | 2018-Present

ANDREW DOAK, M.F.A.

W. LIVETERM.DOAK.STUDIO GH. github.com/andrewdoak Ll. https://www.linkedin.com/in/doak-andrew/ M. 615-957-2341 E. andrew@doak.studio

Deliver customer orders efficiently and adaptably in a high-volume, results-driven delivery environment Achieved top metrics in volume, (when these were shared), frequently complimented on communication style, which makes coworkers' jobs easier to do and collaboration a pleasure

EDUCATOR & LAB ASSISTANT LATITUDE Chicago | 2016-2018

Proposed, planned, and delivered workshops in advanced printmaking; complimented by fellow professor on the quality of teaching materials

Spearheaded new revenue streams & educational offerings

Managed a fast-paced, technically complex studio while troubleshooting hardware and software, advising clients on technical and conceptual matters, accounting, and tracking inventory

Crafted clear, thorough, detailed studio updates for management and staff (frequently singled out for this strength in meetings)

PROFESSOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY McHenry County College | 2012-2015

Conceived, developed, and delivered a technically and creatively rigorous curriculum that was also inclusive. Solicited regular feedback adapted changes to cater to diverse learners

Saved thousands of dollars on printing costs through efficiently managing material use without sacrificing learning. Reinvested surplus funds into transformative studio improvements (doubled inventory).

Oversaw production of award-winning student magazine, Voices

Brought LinkedIn Learning asynchronous education platform to campus

EDUCATION

CRANBROOK ACADEMY OF ART

Master of Fine Arts, Photography Merit scholarship

SEWANEE: UNIVERSITY OF THE SOUTH

Bachelor of Arts, Photography and German

Magna cum laude, Honors in majors, Wilkins merit scholarship

UNIVERSITY OF HAMBURG

Scholarship from the Federation of German-American Clubs for study abroad. Topics included: German, Art History, Italian, and Film Studies

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

German (fluent), Italian (proficient), Spanish (basic)

AWARDS/HONORS

2005. Fulbright Scholarship, Germany 2003. Guggenheim Museology Internship, Italy

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

CHICAGO TOOL LIBRARY | 2023 September - Present
CHICAGO INDUSTRIAL ARTS AND DESIGN CENTER (CIADC) | 2023 July - Present
MAXWELL ST. COMMUNITY GARDEN | 2018 - Present

- Common strengths shared across all work: patience, planning, precision, flexibility, communication with diverse audiences, open-mindedness, active listening, teamwork, and tenacity
- Currently discussing website goals (as a developer) with garden stakeholders
- Active participant in a collaborative update of the Chicago Tool Library's lending software, Circulate (LINK)